Finding Aid for Charles Fey papers, 1914-1970
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Charles Fey papers 1914-1970
Fey, Charles.
851324 Aa 2
Birmingham, Michigan, businessman and Masonic historian; correspondence, research materials, and writings on freemasonry; also materials on other research interests, notably the history of Royal Oak and Royal Oak Township.
9 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Charles Fey (donor no. 3275 ).
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Charles Fey was an Oakland County businessman and historian of freemasonry in Michigan.
The Charles Fey collection is comprised of correspondence conducted in the course of his research into the history of freemasonry in Michigan and in Oakland County in particular. The collection also includes extensive materials about individual masons. The collection is arranged into the following series: Scottish Rite Masonry in Michigan; Knight Templars in Michigan; Masonry in Oakland County, Michigan; Royal Arch and Grand Arch Masons in Michigan; Early Masonry and Leading Masons in Michigan; Masonic History; and Other research and personal interests.
Subjects:
Birmingham (Mich.); Chicago Pneumatic Tool Company.; Congregational churches--Michigan--Birmingham.; Detroit (Mich.)--Church history.; Episcopal Church--Michigan--Detroit.; Freemasonry--Michigan.; Knights Templar (Masonic order); Mariners' Church of Detroit (Detroit, Mich.); Michigan--Capital and capitol.; Oakland County (Mich.); Royal Oak (Mich.: Township); Scottish Rite (Masonic Order); Townsite Community Congregational Church (Birmingham, Mich.)
- Scottish Rite Masonry in Michigan
  - Correspondence 1948-1956, 16 folders (Box 1)
    (folders 1-16)
  - Correspondence with biographical data 1953-1954
    (arranged alphabetically)
    - A (Box 1)
      (folder 17)
      (subjects include: John Quincy Adams, George E. Aiken, John Motte Arnold)
    - B (Box 1)
      (folder 18)
      (subjects include: Enich Bancker, William H. Barse, Robert Bird, Edward Breitung, Charles H. Brown, Demetrius R. Brown, Thomas G. Brownell, Edward S. Brownson, Carlos Burchard, Edwin Burdick, Edward Worthington Burnap, Richard Augustus Bury, Augustus S. Butler)
    - C (Box 1)
      (folder 19)
      (subjects include: William M. Cahoon, Enos Canniff, Harmon A. Chamberlain, James H. Cole, James S. Conklin, William Corbin, Joseph B. Cornell, Solomin S. Curry)
    - D (Box 1)
      (folder 20)
      (subjects include: Francis Darrow, Perry Joshua Davis, Andrew DeForest, Benjamin F. Doughty, John Duncan, William A. Dunn)
    - F (Box 1)
      (folder 21)
      (subjects include: James Fenton, Joseph Fisk, James F. Foley, Colley Alexander Foster, Perrin V. Fox)
    - G (Box 1)
      (folder 22)
      (subjects include: George H. Gale, George Geppert, Mahlon A. Gibbs, Charles Frost Gibson)
    - H (Box 1)
      (folder 23)
      (subjects include: Oscar F. Hamet, Henry L. Harrison, Henry Speed Harrison, Hannibal Hart, Eratus R. Hascall, George Warren Hayden, John Hayden, William T. Hess, James Waterman Hopkins, Charles D. Howard)
    - I-J (Box 1)
      (folder 24)
      (subjects include: William Powers Innes, Lyman P. Jackson, Chester B. Jones, Charles T. Joslin)
    - K (Box 1)
      (folder 25)
      (subjects include: John D. Jennings, Andrew James Kellog, James M. Kelly, Zina Pitcher King, Hollis F. Knapp)
    - L (Box 1)
      (folder 26)
      (subjects include: Richard Lord, Judson C. Lowell)
    - M (Box 1)
      (folder 27)
      (subjects include: G.W. McCormick, Addison McElcheron, Michail Burke McGee, John McKay, Daniel McVitchie, H.P. Merrill, C.C. Merryweather, Abraham Tolles Metcalf, Clement F. Miller, Anson Bushnell Miner, E.W. Mixer, Francis Marriam Moore, John H. Morrison)
    - N-O (Box 1)
      (folder 28)
      (subjects include: A.K. Nash, Alfred B. Oaks, John P. Outhwaite)
    - P (Box 1)
      (folder 29)
      (subjects include: Albert Samuel Parks, Michail C.T. Plesser, William Josiah Pollard, Charles Henry Pomeroy, Benjamin Porter, Foster Pratt, James B. Pratt)
    - R (Box 1)
      (folder 30)
      (subjects include: Christian Rath, Lewis Cass Risdon, William H. Rood, Benjamin Franklin Rose)
    - S (Box 1)
      (folder 31)
      (subjects include: Eugene Griffith St. Clair, James Selkirk, Samuel Klesey Selkirk, Carlos D. Sheldon, George Dudley Smith, Sylvester B. Smith, Henry Hinckley Stafford, John Staley, J.F. Stevens, Silas England Stone, William O. Stone, Benjamin B. Sutphin, William F. Swift)
    - T (Box 1)
      (folder 32)
      (subjects include: O.L. Teachout, Perer Teller, W.A. Tolchard, James B. Tomlinson)
    - U-V (Box 1)
      (folder 33)
      (subjects include: Reneselaer S. Updyke, Stewart A. Van Dusen, James Videtto, George Voorhis)
    - W (Box 1)
      (folder 34)
      (subjects include: William L. Webber, James R. Webster, Stephen Merrit Webster, William Wheat, Charles M. Wheeler, Samuel W. Wheeler, J.J. Williams, Fred P. Wormley)
  - Other papers undated, 3 folders (Box 1)
    (folders 35-37)
- Knight Templars in Michigan
  - Correspondence
    - 1952 (Box 1)
      (folder 38)
    - 1956 (Box 1)
      (folder 39)
    - 1957 (Box 1)
      (folder 40)
    - 1958 (Box 1)
      (folder 41)
    - Undated (Box 1)
      (folder 42)
  - Correspondence with biographical data 1947-1958
    - A-B (Box 1)
      (folder 43)
      (subjects include: Wales Adams, Luman Russell Atwater, George Rice Burdick)
    - C (Box 1)
      (folder 44)
      (subjects include: Reuben S. Cheney, William H. Clark, Elias D. Cone, John K. Crosswell, Francis H. Cuming)
    - D (Box 1)
      (folder 45)
      (subjects include: J.P. Davis, Martin Davis, Henry Dean, Alexander Downey, James A. Dyer)
    - F (Box 1)
      (folder 46)
      (subjects include: George A. Fitch, John B. Flower)
    - H (Box 1)
      (folder 47)
      (subjects include: Frederick Hall)
    - L (Box 1)
      (folder 48)
      (subjects include: David S. Leavitt, George W. Lusk)
    - M (Box 1)
      (folder 49)
      (subjects include: John McConnell, Franklin W. May, Calvin Merrill, Alexander Mooney)
    - O (Box 1)
      (folder 50)
      (subjects include: John M. Oliver)
    - R (Box 2)
      (folder 51)
      (subjects include: Wyllis C. Ransom, John Ritchie, Hugh Rollins)
    - S (Box 2)
      (folder 52)
      (subjects include: Robert R. Salter, James Wilson Sligh, George A. Strong)
    - T (Box 2)
      (folder 53)
      (subjects include: William H. Tanner, Lyman B. Townsend)
    - W (Box 2)
      (folder 54)
      (subjects include: Sylvester Walker, Moses W. Ward, Sylveston Watters, William K. Wheeler, David Winchester)
  - Detroit Commandery no. 1 of the Knights Templars 1947-1948 (Box 2)
    (folder 55)
- Masonry in Oakland County, Michigan
  - Correspondence 1939-1949, 11 folders (Box 2)
    (folders 56-66)
  - Miscellanea, 4 folders (Box 2)
    (folders 67-70)
  - Correspondence with biographical data 1941-1952
    - A-B (Box 2)
      (folder 71)
      (subjects include: Edwin I. Arms, James Baldwin, James Ball, W.J. Bartow, Martin H. Bently, Oscar Bently, Harry R. Brace)
    - C (Box 2)
      (folder 72)
      (subjects include: Elijah B. Clark, Charles A. Crane)
    - E (Box 2)
      (folder 73)
      (subjects include: Charles M. Eldridge, David Elliot)
    - F (Box 2)
      (folder 74)
      (subjects include: Frank W. Fifield)
    - G (Box 2)
      (folder 75)
      (subjects include: William Gass, Gideon Gates)
    - H (Box 2)
      (folder 76)
      (subjects include: John B. Hamilton, Thomas Head, William Holcomb, Charles Hoodless, Henry L. Horton, Warner Howland, Robert S. Hutton)
    - J-K (Box 2)
      (folder 77)
      (subjects include: Henry Hamilton Jackson, David Ketchum)
    - L (Box 2)
      (folder 78)
      (subjects include: Laverne J. Levansler, Jacob Loop)
    - M-N (Box 2)
      (folder 79)
      (subjects include: Allan McKay, Horace H. Markham, Elisha H. Marsh, Francis Homer Newton)
    - R-S (Box 2)
      (folder 80)
      (subjects include: Claude A. Russell, Henry R. Russell, Erastus Spaulding)
    - V (Box 2)
      (folder 81)
      (subjects include: William V. Vliet)
    - W (Box 2)
      (folder 82)
      (subjects include: (A.C. Washburn, James K. Weeks)
  - Royal Oak Lodge No. 464 1931-1932, 1956-1957, 1962, 4 folders (Box 2)
    (folders 83-86)
- Royal Arch and Grand Arch Masons in Michigan
  - Michigan Grand Lodge, Royal Arch Masons
    - Correspondence 1945-1948, 1956 (Box 3)
      (folder 89)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 3)
      (folder 90)
  - Grand Arch Masons in Michigan
    - Biographical Data
      - A-B (Box 3)
        (folder 91)
        (subjects include: John Anderson, John G. Bond, Calvin Britain, Henry O. Bronson, Jonathan Brown, Peter Brown)
      - C (Box 3)
        (folder 92)
        (subjects include: Lewis Cass, Leverette Church)
      - D (Box 3)
        (folder 93)
        (subjects include: Sylvester Day, Jacob D. Dutton, James A. Dyer)
      - I (Box 3)
        (folder 94)
        (subjects include: Calib J. Ingersol, Robert Irwin)
      - J (Box 3)
        (folder 95)
        (subjects include: Czar Jones, William Jones)
      - K (Box 3)
        (folder 96)
        (subjects include: Edmund Kirby, Reynolds M. Kirby)
      - L-M (Box 3)
        (folder 97)
        (subjects include: Phillip LeCuyer, David G. McClure, Marston Morrel)
      - P (Box 3)
        (folder 98)
        (subjects include: John Palmer, Benjamin Porter, John Frederick Porter)
      - R (Box 3)
        (folder 99)
        (subjects include: Paul B. Ring, Chester Root)
      - S (Box 3)
        (folder 100)
        (subjects include: Samuel Selden, Abiel Silver, Jacob Silver, Benjamin Stead)
      - T (Box 3)
        (folder 101)
        (subjects include: Sterling A. Turner)
      - W (Box 3)
        (folder 102)
        (subjects include: Samuel W. Walker, John W. Wittenmyer)
  - Masonic Grand Lodge chaplains 1948-1957
    - Samuel Silsby (Box 3)
      (folder 103)
    - Daniel Michael (Box 3)
      (folder 104)
    - Ashbel Wells and Oliver Cromwell Comstock (Box 3)
      (folder 105)
- Early Masonry and Leading Masons in Michigan
  - Early Masonry
    - Miscellanea, 3 folders (Box 3)
      (folders 106-108)
    - Correspondence with biographical data 1946-1962
      - A (Box 3)
        (folder 109)
        (subjects include: Dr. George Christian Anthon, William Arundel, John Askin)
      - C (Box 3)
        (folder 110)
        (subjects include: Richard Cartwright, John Christie)
      - D-E (Box 3)
        (folder 111)
        (subjects include: William Edgar)
      - F (Box 3)
        (folder 112)
        (subjects include: Sampson Fleming)
      - G (Box 3)
        (folder 113)
        (subjects include: Alexander Grant)
      - H-Hari (Box 3)
        (folder 114)
        (subjects include: Beverley Drake Harison, George Harison)
      - Harj-I (Box 3)
        (folder 115)
        (subjects include: Josias Harper, Hugh Heward)
      - J-M (Box 3)
        (folder 116)
        (subjects include: Benjamin James, Richard McNeil, Thomas Mathews)
      - P (Box 3)
        (folder 117)
        (subjects include: John Porteous, Augustine Provost)
      - R (Box 3)
        (folder 118)
        (subjects include: Thomas Robison, Robert Rogers)
      - S (Box 3)
        (folder 119)
        (subjects include: Jacob Schieffelin, Jonathan Schieffelin, Richard Shuckburgh, Thomas Swords)
      - T (Box 3)
        (folder 120)
        (subjects include: Isaac Todd)
  - Leading Masons in Michigan
    - Correspondence with biographical data 1946-1962
      - A (Box 4)
        (folder 121)
        (subjects include: M.A. Aldrich, Albert Arthur Alford)
      - B-Bk (Box 4)
        (folder 122)
        (subjects include: John Barber, John Barney, Noah Beach, Jonathan Berry, David Bixby)
      - Bl-C (Box 4)
        (folder 123)
        (subjects include: Francis Asbury Blades, Stillman Blanchard, Simeon B. Brown, William S. Brown)
      - C (Box 4)
        (folder 124)
        (subjects include: Joseph Campau, Nathan B. Carpenter, Thomas Scott Clark)
      - E (Box 4)
        (folder 125)
        (subjects include: Abraham Edwards, Nathaniel Buel Eldredge, Peleg Ewell)
      - F (Box 4)
        (folder 126)
        (subjects include: John Farrar)
      - G (Box 4)
        (folder 127)
        (subjects include: James Ganson, George F. Gardner, John Gorham, George W. Grumond)
      - H (Box 4)
        (folder 128)
        (subjects include: James A. Hahn, Jonas Harrison, Douglass Houghton, Henry Jackson Hunt)
      - J-K (Box 4)
        (folder 129)
        (subjects include: Nathaniel Poole Jacobs, Albert Henry Jordan, Charles Kellogg, Dwight Kellogg)
      - L (Box 4)
        (folder 130)
        (subjects include: Isaac Leonard)
      - M (Box 4)
        (folder 131)
        (subjects include: Alexander Macomb, Harvey Mellen, John N. Mellen, Leander Mellen, Richard S. Mellen, William Morgan)
      - P (Box 4)
        (folder 132)
        (subjects include: George W. Peck, Benjamin F. Pope, Gustavus W. Pope)
      - R (Box 4)
        (folder 133)
        (subjects include: William Richardson, Horace Smith Roberts, George W. Robertson, Ezra Rood, Henry Rumsey)
      - S-Shel (Box 4)
        (folder 134)
        (subjects include: Edward Sawyer, William McDowell Scott, John P. Sheldon)
      - Shem-T (Box 4)
        (folder 135)
        (subjects include: Samuel Sherwood, Solomon Sibley, Robert Smart, Abner Comstock Smith)
      - T (Box 4)
        (folder 136)
        (subjects include: John Holmes Thayer)
      - V (Box 4)
        (folder 137)
        (subjects include: Killian Henry VanRensselaer)
      - W-Wj (Box 4)
        (folder 138)
        (subjects include: Smith Weeks, Allyn Weston, Gersham Mott Williams, Oliver Williams)
      - Wk-Z (Box 4)
        (folder 139)
        (subjects include: Augustus Brevoort Woodward, Benjamin Woodworth)
    - Correspondence with Grand Council Royal and Select Master Masons of Michigan 1947-1960 (Box 4)
      (folder 140)
- Masonic History
  - General Masonic History correspondence 1941-1966, 23 folders (Box 4)
    (folders 141-163)
  - Freemasonry in Michigan
    - Miscellanea, 4 folders (Box 5)
      (folders 164-167)
    - Biographical data (A-Z) (Box 5)
      (folder 168)
      (subjects include: John Anderson, Daniel S. Bacon, James Burns, Abram C. Canniff, Marshall Chapin, Henry S. Cole, Harry Conant, Levi Cook, Orville Cook, Louis Davenport, Abraham Edwards, John Garrison, Shadrach Gillett, Elliot Gray, Felix Hinchman, Laban Jenks, DeGarmo Jones, George Wallace Jones, Isaac Lee, Charles Noble, Lucien A. Smith, Noah M. Wells, Obed White, Henry Whiting)
    - Manuscript of book entitled "History of Freemasonry in Michigan" by Charles Fey (Box 5)
      (folder 169)
    - Miscellaneous printed matter, 3 folders (Box 5)
      (folders 170-172)
    - Miscellanea, 3 folders (Box 5)
      (folders 173-175)
    - Clippings (Box 5)
      (folder 176)
  - Masonry outside Michigan, correspondence with biographical data 1950-1959 (Box 5)
    (folder 177)
    (subjects include: Henry Beasley, Henry B. Brevoort, Henry Cuyler, Henry Andrew Francken, William Gamble, Thomas Lynot, Washington Shirley, Samuel Stringer, Francis Joseph Von Pfister)
  - Biographical research
    - William Beaumont
      - Correspondence 1955-1970, 3 folders (Box 5)
        (folders 178-180)
      - Miscellanea (Box 5)
        (folder 181)
      - Printed material, 2 folders (Box 5)
        (folders 182-183)
    - William Burt
      - Correspondence and miscellanea 1944-1959 (Box 5)
        (folder 184)
      - Miscellanea (Box 5)
        (folder 185)
    - DeWitt Clinton (Box 5)
      (folder 186)
    - George B. Ensworth (Box 5)
      (folder 187)
    - John Francis Hamtramck
      - Correspondence 1959-1963 (Box 5)
        (folder 188)
      - Miscellanea (Box 5)
        (folder 189)
    - Josiah Henson
      - Correspondence 1949-1951 (Box 5)
        (folder 190)
      - Biographical data (Box 5)
        (folder 191)
      - Printed miscellanea (Box 5)
        (folder 192)
    - David Burnham Tracy
      - Correspondence 1953-1961, 4 folders (Box 6)
        (folders 193-196)
      - Biographical data (Box 6)
        (folder 197)
    - William T. Tracy (Box 6)
      (folder 198)
    - Andrew G. Whitney
      - Correspondence (Box 6)
        (folder 199)
      - Biographical data (Box 6)
        (folder 200)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence 1933, 1940-1966, 6 folders (Box 6)
    (folders 201-206)
  - Miscellaneous Masonic materials
    - Miscellanea (Box 6)
      (folder 207)
    - Masonry in Mexico
      - Correspondence 1914-1920 (Box 6)
        (folder 208)
      - Miscellanea, 2 folders (Box 6)
        (folders 209-210)
    - History of hymns sung at Michigan Grand Lodge, correspondence about 1959-1960 (Box 6)
      (folder 211)
    - Masonic Education Plan of Royal Oak Lodge No. 464, 2 folders (Box 6)
      (folders 212-213)
    - Old Detroit City Hall (Box 6)
      (folder 214)
    - State Capitol Buildings in Michigan, correspondence about 1947-1948 (Box 6)
      (folder 215)
    - French and Indian Masonry
      - Correspondence about 1951-1965 (Box 6)
        (folder 216)
      - Miscellanea (Box 6)
        (folder 217)
    - Mariners' Church in Detroit (Box 6)
      (folder 218)
    - Article by Louis H. Fead entitled "Masonic Law" (Box 6)
      (folder 219)
    - Printed miscellanea concerning history of Freemasonry, 2 folders (Box 6)
      (folders 220-221)
    - Miscellaneous articles from Masonic periodicals, 8 folders (Box 6)
      (folders 222-229)
    - Miscellaneous document re Masonic history, 2 folders Photostats, positive (Box 6)
      (folders 230-231)
    - Masonry in Denmark, papers 1947-1951 (Box 7)
      (folder 232)
    - George Washington and Freemasonry, papers 1960-1967 (Box 7)
      (folder 233)
    - Masonry in New York, papers 1969-1970 (Box 7)
      (folder 234)
    - American flag, and the seal and flag of Michigan, papers 1946-1956 (Box 7)
      (folder 235)
    - Harris Hampden Hickman, papers 1959-1963 (Box 7)
      (folder 236)
    - John Curtis, papers 1943-1952 (Box 7)
      (folder 237)
    - Grand Lodge of Michigan, papers 1959-1963 (Box 7)
      (folder 238)
    - Reginald V. Harris, secretary of the Canadian Masonic Research Association, correspondence 1948-1969 (Box 7)
      (folder 239)
    - Order of the Red Cross of Constantine, papers 1954-1962 (Box 7)
      (folder 240)
    - Detroit Masonic Temple, and other Masonic affairs, papers 1968-1970 (Box 7)
      (folder 241)
    - Early Freemasonry in central New York, papers undated (Box 7)
      (folder 242)
    - History of Masonry in Michigan, miscellanea 1959-1969, 3 folders (Box 7)
      (folders 243-245)
    - Miscellanea (Box 7)
      (folder 246)
  - Research articles:
    - "Lincoln and Freemasonry: Historical records prove mutual respect" (Box 7)
      (folder 247)
    - "Heraldry of Freemasonry" (Box 7)
      (folder 248)
    - "Daniel B. Taylor and his Candle" (Box 7)
      (folder 249)
    - "Early Detroit and the Fire of 1805" (Box 7)
      (folder 250)
    - "Harris Hampden Hickman" (Box 7)
      (folder 251)
    - "Dr. William McDowell Scott" (Box 7)
      (folder 252)
    - "Early History of Freemasonry in Central New York" (Box 7)
      (folder 253)
    - "Monument erected to the memory of M.W. Horace Smith Roberts, P.G.M." (Box 7)
      (folder 254)
    - "Meeting and possible meeting places of Stony Creek Lodge No. 7, 3, 5, now Rochester Lodge No.5" (Box 7)
      (folder 255)
    - "Freemasonry in Upper Canada and the 1812 War" (Box 7)
      (folder 256)
    - "The Michigan Railroad Era" (Box 7)
      (folder 257)
    - "Did the French Masons influence the Indians Mit-Tah Masonry?" (Box 7)
      (folder 258)
    - "Stony Creek Memorial, Rochester, Michigan" (Box 7)
      (folder 259)
    - "Grand Chaplains Grand Lodge of Michigan" (Box 7)
      (folder 260)
    - "Michigan Freemasonry and the Civil War" (Box 7)
      (folder 261)
    - "Solomon Sibley" (Box 7)
      (folder 262)
    - "Grand Lecturers of Michigan" (Box 7)
      (folder 263)
    - "Worshipful Masters of Zion Lodge, No. 1, 1794-1829" (Box 7)
      (folder 264)
    - "Hymns sung at Grand Lodge" (Box 7)
      (folder 265)
    - "Killian Henry Van Rensselaer" (Box 7)
      (folder 266)
    - "Dr. Richard Schuckburgh, author of Yankee Doodle" (Box 7)
      (folder 267)
    - "Dewitt Clinton" (Box 7)
      (folder 268)
    - "List of officers contained in a petition to transport settlers and their families to the settlement at Detroit" (Box 7)
      (folder 269)
    - "The Academic Regalia" (Box 7)
      (folder 270)
    - "Reports of the History Committee of the Grand Chapter" (Box 7)
      (folder 271)
    - "John L. Whiting, First Grand Secretary of the Grand Lodge of Michigan" (Box 7)
      (folder 272)
    - "Rev. David Burnham Tracy and his membership in the Red Cross of Constantine" (Box 7)
      (folder 273)
      (missing)
    - "Detroit in 1793" (Box 7)
      (folder 274)
    - "Captain John Clark" (Box 7)
      (folder 275)
    - "Ammi W. Wright, Donor of the Masonic Home in Alma, Michigan" (Box 7)
      (folder 276)
    - "Birth of the Ancient Accepted Scottish Rite in America..." (Box 7)
      (folder 277)
    - "Casimir Pulaski" (Box 7)
      (folder 278)
    - "Local and Grand Lodge Buildings" (Box 7)
      (folder 279)
    - "Simon Girty" (Box 7)
      (folder 280)
    - "Charles Fey" (Box 7)
      (folder 281)
    - "Masonic Side Orders" (Box 8)
      (folder 282)
    - "The Royal Americans of the 60th Regiment" (Box 8)
      (folder 283)
  - Notebook containing biographical material on early Michigan masons (Box 8)
    (folder 284)
  - "Stony Creek Lodge No. 7, now Rochester Lodge No. 5", research paper (Box 8)
    (folder 285)
  - Stony Creek Lodge No. 7, research material 1960-1971 (Box 8)
    (folder 286)
  - Research materials:
    - "Dr. William Beaumont" (Box 8)
      (folder 287)
    - "Sherman Stevens. Father of Royal Oak Village, Mich." (Box 8)
      (folder 288)
    - "Was William Morgan of the Caribbean the same as William Morgan of Batavia?" (Box 8)
      (folder 289)
    - "King Solomon's Temple" (Box 8)
      (folder 290)
    - "William F. Tracy" (Box 8)
      (folder 291)
    - "Rev. Josiah Henson, or the Hero of Uncle Tom's Cabin" (Box 8)
      (folder 292)
    - "Captain John Christie, First Worshipful Master Lodge No. 1, Detroit, Mich. 1764" (Box 8)
      (folder 293)
    - "Michigan Masonic Homes" (Box 8)
      (folder 294)
    - "The Beginning of Freemasonry" (Box 8)
      (folder 295)
    - "Prominent Indians and Freemasonry" (Box 8)
      (folder 296)
    - "Judge Augustus Brevoort Woodward" (Box 8)
      (folder 297)
    - "Col. John Francis Hamtramck, Master Mason" (Box 8)
      (folder 298)
    - "History of the Chicago Pneumatic Tool Co. and its Subsidiaries, 1894-1959" (Box 8)
      (folder 299)
    - Taylor Family (Box 8)
      (folder 300)
    - Dead Sea Scrolls (Box 8)
      (folder 301)
    - John Gilbert, Jr. (Box 8)
      (folder 302)
    - Nathaniel Pullman (Box 8)
      (folder 303)
    - William Morgan (Box 8)
      (folder 304)
  - Research on Oakland County Masonry, papers concerning (Box 8)
    (folder 305)
  - Newspaper clippings (Box 8)
    (folder 306)
  - Newspaper clippings (Box 8)
    (folder 307)
  - Miscellaneous research materials (Box 8)
    (folder 308)
  - The George Washington National Memorial Association (Box 8)
    (folder 309)
  - History of the Conferences of the Grand Master Masons and the Grand Secretaries in North America (Box 8)
    (folder 310)
- Other research and personal interests
  - Royal Oak and Oakland County, Michigan
    - Royal Oak, Michigan history correspondence 1953-1954, 5 folders (Box 9)
      (folders 311-315)